<Document>
# 植物学
植物学者であるあなたの仕事は、シェフが 「代替ソース 」を探すのを止めさせるだけの食料を栽培することだ。小麦をたくさん栽培し、それに飽きたら雑草を栽培する。雑草スムージーを作ったり、イラクサ入りのドリンクを作ったり。植物を育て続ければ、きっとうまくいく！

## シフトの開始
まず、自分の周りにある使用する機械を確認する。シェフと調整し、何か特別なものを栽培してほしいかどうかを確認する。そうでなければ、小麦やバナナなど、栽培したいと思うものを栽培する。また、化学（メドベイ）やバーテンダー、カーゴで売るための植物を育てることもできる。


# 道具
作物を健康に育てるための道具がたくさんある。水耕栽培トレイは、あなたが植物学者としてほとんどの時間を費やす場所です。

## 水耕栽培トレイ
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="hydroponicsTray"/>
</Box>
これは水耕栽培用のトレイで、水で植物を育てる。まずトレイに水を入れ、次に種を入れる。
Hydroponics tray lights indicate different things depending on color and position:
- [color=red]Red Light, Left[/color]: Dead plant that needs re-planting. Use a spade to remove the plant.
- [color=orange]Flashing Orange Light, Center[/color]: The environment is sub-optimal. Check what is affecting the plant by Shift Clicking on it. It is likely weeds but it could be undesirable pressure or lack of oxygen. If weeds, use a mini hoe or spray 1 time with weed spray. Be warned, however, that overuse of weed killers can lead to unhealthy plants, possibly killing them.
- [color=#0336ff]Blue Light, Right[/color]: Needs water. Use bucket on the water tank and fill the tray.
- [color=green]Green Light, Left[/color]: Ready for harvest. Left click to harvest.
- [color=yellow]Yellow Light, Right[/color]: Needs nutrients. Use any fruit and put it into the soil or get EZ nutrients from chemistry.

The lifecycle of a hydroponics tray is the following:
- [color=lightgreen]Empty[/color]: no water, seed or nutrients
- [color=lightgreen]Hydrated[/color]: you've added water to it (e.g. from a bottle or bucket).
- [color=lightgreen]Ready for planting[/color]: you've added water and nutrients to it (i.e. fertilizer).
- [color=lightgreen]Planted[/color]: you've added a seed to it
- [color=lightgreen]Ready for Harvest[/color]: you've waited for the plant to grow
- [color=lightgreen]Sampled[/color]: you've taken a sample (seed)
- [color=lightgreen]Harvested[/color]: you've picked ready plants. Some plants will then grow again. Others will die and need replanting.
- [color=lightgreen]Unhealthy[/color]: You've sampled too many seeds or sprayed it with deadly chemicals. The plant isn't coping too well. It'll continue to grow. Health can be restored by fertilizers or you can cut your losses and extract a seed (plant clippers) and replant.
- [color=lightgreen]Old / Wilted[/color]: the plant has matured and will soon die. It will still be harvestable and you can extract seeds but only for a short duration. Extract the seed and then pluck it out / chop it down.
- [color=lightgreen]Dead[/color]: the plant has been harvested and ceased growing. It should be plucked out / chopped down. No seeds can be extracted.

## Seed Extractor
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SeedExtractor"/>
</Box>
種子を抽出する。作物を入れ、種子を受け取る。


# 植物遺伝学
ナノトレーゼンが知る他のすべての生命体と同様に、植物は遺伝子の中で形質を子孫に伝えます。植物の遺伝子を操作することで、植物学者は植物の健康と収穫量を増加させる望ましい突然変異を持つ品種を作り出すことができる。

## 形質
表現型、すなわち植物の観察可能な特徴や形質の集合は、注意深い観察と研究によって決定することができる。一般的な形質には以下のようなものがある：

- [color=lightgreen]Bioluminescence[/color]: plants with this trait glow in the dark
- [color=lightgreen]High yield[/color]: plants with this trait yield more fruit per harvest
- [color=lightgreen]Less water[/color]: plants with this trait require less water than normal to grow
- [color=lightgreen]Ligneous[/color]: plants with this trait require sharp tools to harvest
- [color=lightgreen]Long life[/color]: plants with this trait live for more harvest cycles before dying
- [color=lightgreen]Low light[/color]: plants with this trait need less light than normal to grow
- [color=lightgreen]Pest resistance[/color]: plants with this trait are more resistant to pests
- [color=lightgreen]Seedless[/color]: plants with this trait do not produce viable seeds
- [color=lightgreen]Weed resistance[/color]: plants with this trait suppress weed growth

植物を育てて観察するだけで、その表現型を決定することができる！1866年、遺伝学の父グレゴール・メンデルはこうして植物を研究した。

## 突然変異
[color=cyan]不安定変異原[/color]で処理された植物は、ランダムに遺伝子変異を起こし、遺伝子が変化して形質が変わることがある。突然変異を起こした植物は、種子を収穫することで保存することができます。

不安定変異原を使えば使うほど、より多くの変異を得ることができる。多くの遺伝子は植物の生存に不可欠であるため、ほとんどの突然変異は植物を枯死させる。

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnstableMutagenChemistryBottle"/>
</Box>

## 交配
[color=cyan]滅菌綿棒[/color]を使って、ある植物から別の植物に花粉を移すことができる。交配された植物は、形質を移すチャンスがある。花粉は粘着性があるので、綿棒の再利用には注意すること！

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BoxMouthSwab"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DiseaseSwab"/>
</Box>

## 化学物質
化学物質の中には、植物に特別な影響を与えるものがある。

[textlink="すべての植物化学物質を見るには、ここをクリックしてください。" link="Botanical"]

<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Dylovene"/>
<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Cryoxadone"/>
<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Necrosol"/>
<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Phalanximine"/>
<GuideReagentGroupEmbed Group="Botanical"/>
  
</Document>
